Eric Paulz

https://epaulz.github.io

303 Church St. #8, Central, SC 29630

864-243-6767 | eric.c.paulz@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

To find a full-time, entry-level position in which I can utilize the software development, data science, and many other skills that I have gained through school and work experience. I love writing code, but I also enjoy being engaged and interacting with people in order to achieve optimal solutions.

EDUCATION

Clemson University - Computer Science, B.S.

Clemson, SC

Relevant Courses: Algorithm Design/Analysis

Graduation: December 2018

Linear Algebra

GPA: 3.45

Cloud Computing Architecture Human & Computer Interaction

SKILLS

Software Development - C++, Python, C, Java

Data Science - Python (Pandas, iPython, Scikit-learn, matplotlib), SQL, Hadoop, Hive, Alation, Tableau

Agile - Confluence, JIRA, Scrum, Sprints

IoT – Splunk, Node-RED, Raspberry Pi, MQTT

Environments - Linux, Unix, Windows, Bash

Miscellaneous - 3D printing, HTML, VBA, LaTeX

EXPERIENCE

BMW Group - innovation[LAB]

Greenville, SC

IT Innovations & Research Intern

May 2018 - August 2018

- Conducted an IoT experiment using a Raspberry Pi to study the effect of edge computing on device resource load as well as network effect.
- Used a sentiment analysis library in Python to analyze customer emotions based on J.D. Power reports.
- Used big data tools to calculate take rates of options on used vehicles for manual pricing.

BMW Manufacturing

Greer, SC

Material Control Intern

May 2017 - August 2017

- Created VBA macros from scratch to boost efficiency of daily tasks within a logistics department.
- Built an interactive map that showed location and other information about parts suppliers.

Clemson Online

Clemson, SC

Educational Media & Web Support Intern

January 2017 – April 2017

Performed web maintenance and improvements on a portion of the Clemson University website.